Lillian Wakefield

+52 1 55 2205 0045 | Mexico City, Mexico

lilllianwakefield@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/lillian-wakefield/ | https://github.com/LillianWakefield

Summary

Throughout my professional career, I have pursued a wide variety of cross-disciplinary interests. I started in the scientific field as an environmental consultant before pursuing teaching and have recently transitioned into software engineering. I draw on all of my past experiences to be an effective communicator, manager, and critical problem solver.

Experience

Director of Career Services | DigitalCrafts | February 2018 – Present | Mexico City, D.F.

- Provide student outcome data in keeping with the industry standards as outlined by the Council of Integrity Results Reporting
- · Gather and report internal diversity data, an independent initiative that resulted in a scholarship program for woman and veterans
- · Support the student job search process, including providing individual feedback on career assets and fostering employer network relationships
- · Create quality engaging content to support the company including blog posts and newsletters

Private Tutor | Geek Tutoring | August 2016 – February 2018 | Mexico City, D.F.

- · Worked with students grade five through twelve to increase understanding and performance in English, math, physics, biology, chemistry, and SAT Prep
- · Designed individual and group classes based on students' needs, goals, and learning styles while fostering the skills necessary to achieve independent academic success through high school and beyond

Research Assistant | Integral Consulting, Inc. | June 2014 – March 2016 | Portland, OR Ongoing or Confidential Litigation Projects:

- · Compiled and consolidated existing baseline datasets to develop client specific databases
- · Provided onsite logistics management for human and environmental field sampling
- · Assembled, verified and summarized technical documentation to support litigation

Select Completed Project, BP Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill:

- · Managed team responding to user requests for Gulf of Mexico Research Initiative database repairs
- · Performed comprehensive data quality analysis, fitness, and management for the database
- · Interpreted and verified numerous field sampling plans and methodologies across a wide range of scope, infrastructure and sample media
- · Data published for this project is available online at https://data.gulfresearchinitiative.org

Staff Scientist | D-Max Engineering | December 2013 – May 2014 | San Diego, CA

- Performed storm water inspections at industrial and commercial facilities to assess the compliance status of businesses as outlined by the city of San Diego Storm Water Division, inspections involved educating local business owners about their environmental impact and best management practices
- · Monitored outfall points and completed upstream investigations as needed to determine the source of water flow during site investigations

Research Assistant | Scripps Institution of Oceanography | January 2012 – September 2013 | San Diego, CA

- Analyzed data to determine ecological pressures on marine life through visual identification of acoustic monitoring using Long Term Spectral Average plots
- · Deployed and retrieved autonomous acoustic recording devices at site-specific locations off the California coast, on-site duties included field testing and troubleshooting of instrumentation to ensure sample quality
- · Completed digital documentation project to update data management system while identifying and eliminating inconsistencies

Skills & Abilities

- · Programming languages and frameworks include HTML/CSS, JavasScript, jQuery, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, Express, Node.js, AWS, Go, Python, R, and Matlab
- · Proficient in MS Office, including Excel
- · SIELE certified B2 level Spanish

Education

Certification in Full-Stack Web Development | DigitalCrafts | August 2018

· Immersive six-month web development learning program

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Chemistry | University of California, San Diego | June 2013

- · Recipient of the CALIT2 Undergraduate Summer Scholars award
- · On-site XRF field specialist for the three-month Edom Lowlands Regional Archaeology project in Jordan